M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid C0171
Manuscripts Division
- Series 1: Artwork and Manuscripts, 1700-2999; 32 boxes; 141 items; 12 Volumes
  - Subseries 1A: Artwork and Oversize Manuscripts, 1822-1944 August 21; 18 boxes; 1 item
    - Various Authors and Artists, 1844 February 26-1937 November 5; 3 boxes
      - Two caricatures of Thomas Hughes -- one from the July 10, 1872 issue of The Hornet, titled "Master Tom Brown" and matted, and the other from Vanity Fair, dated 1872 June 8, with a biographical opinion written by Jehu Junior pasted on the back, 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 14)
      - Printed leaflets (13) for and (1) against the re-election of Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton as Lord Rector of the University of Glasgow, Scotland, in 1858, as well as four leaflets (mounted on stiff paper) nominating Charles Dickens as Lord Rector by the Committee of Independent Students, 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 15)
        1. "Letters to the Conservative Club, by a Living Junius." 16 lines of anti-Lytton verse, printed on blue paper. 22.5 by 16 cm. 2. "An Ode for the Independents.... Vote for Bulwer." 20 lines of verse. 22.5 by 14.5 cm. 3. "A Peculiar Song by a Peculiar Man." 40 lines of anti-Lytton verse. 26.5 by 15 cm. 4. "A Poetical Dirge." 36 lines of pro-Lytton verse. 28 by 22.5 cm. 5. "What has Bulwer Lytton Done for Students' Rights? Nothing.... Uphold Shaftesbury and Downright Truth." Liberal Association, 8th November, 1858. 28.5 by 22.5 cm. 6. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow.... Vote for Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton." Conservative Club Committee Rooms, November 8th, 1858. Printed on green paper. 28.5 by 23 cm. 7. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow.... by enthusiastically returning The Right Hon. Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton." Conservative Club Committee Rooms, 8th November, 1858. George Richardson, Printer to the University. Printed on pink paper. 29 by 22.5 cm. 8. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow.... Vote for Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton." Conservative Club Committee Rooms, 10th November, 1858. Printed on yellow paper. 28.5 by 22.5 cm. 9. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow.... Vote for Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton." Conservative Club Committee Rooms, November 11, 1858. Printed on pink paper. 29 by 23 cm. 10. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow. The Conservative Club desires to take the earliest opportunity of reprobating, in the strongest terms, the proceedings of last night's Meeting." Conservative Club Committee Rooms, November 11, 1858. Printed on pink paper. 22.5 by 29. 5 cm. 11. "Hoop de Doodin Do." The Conservative Club Rooms, November 12, 1858. 50 lines of pro-Lytton verse, printed on yellow paper. 22.5 by 14 cm. 12. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow.... Vote for The Right Hon. Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton." Conservative Club Committee Rooms, November 15, 1858. Printed on pink paper. 23 by 29 cm. 13. "To the Students of the University of Glasgow. Gentlemen, The Conservative Club beg to congratulate the supporters of Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton upon the success which has crowned their efforts during the recent Election.. ." 28.5 by 22.5 cm.
        Bibliography
        For an account of the election, with reproductions of 5 other posters in the Dickens section of the Parrish Collection, see Ada B. Nisbet, "Dickens Loses an Election," The Princeton University Library Chronicle, Vol. 11, No. 4 (Summer 1950), 157-176.
      - Booth's Theatre Bulletin (for week ending December 14th, 1872) of Lord Lytton's play, The Lady of Lyons, or, Love and Pride, starring the "Celebrated Tragedienne," Miss Neilson (mounted on brittle cardboard, 2 pieces have broken off), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 16)
      - Printed announcement for the "General Theatrical Fund 9th Anniversary, Monday, 1848 April 17, Sir Edward Bulwer Lytton, Bart. in the Chair", 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 17)
      - Illustrated scenes from Lord Lytton's play, Money, a collection of printed quotes about Money compiled in "Theatre Royal, Hay-market, Opinions of the Public Press," and a clipping reviewing the "Command Performance" of Money at Drury Lane for the King and the Kaiser of Germany by The Daily Telegraph, 1911 May 18; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 18)
      - Seven London theatre broadsides and two theatre circulars ( The Play Bill and The Footlights ), ranging in dates from, 1852-1870; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 19)
      - A printed advertisement by T. B. Peterson & Brothers of Philadelphia announcing: "Published this day! February 18th, 1871: Charles Dickens' Last Book! The Mystery of Edwin Drood !" along with Mad Monkton and Other Stories by Wilkie Collins and T. A. Trollope's The Sealed Packet, etc. and an advertising poster for "The Chimes! A Goblin Story of Some Bells that Rang an Old Year Out and a New Year In By Charles Dickens", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 20)
      - Printed leaflet for a "Strictly Private Amateur Performance" of Ben Jonson's comedy, Every Man in his Humour, on 1845 November 15, starring Charles Dickens, among others, 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 21)
      - A poetic address to "Charles Dickens, Esq. on the occasion of his presiding at the Annual Soirée of the Mechanics' Institution, Liverpool, Monday, 1844 February 26," printed on silk, 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 22)
      - Two copies of a "Charles Dickens as Captain Bobadill" illustration (from an unidentified periodical) and a caricature of "Charles Dickens -- par Gill" on the front page of L'Eclipse, 1868 June 14; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 23)
      - An oversize poster titled "The Great International Walking-Match of February 29, 1868" (with "Charles Dickens" among the signatures) is contained inside an oversize, cardboard-backed, four-flap enclosure, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 94)
      - An oversize pen-and-chalk drawing of Charles Kingsley's wife, Frances Grenfell Kingsley, inscribed on verso "Mrs. Kingsley on the sofa reading the paper"; unidentified pen-and-ink drawing of Mount Vesuvius, undated; 1 box (Box 87)
    - J. G. Marks Album of Frederick Walker and William Makepeace Thackeray Illustrations, circa 1861-1871; 1 item 38.1 x 48.3 cm (Item 153)
      The album contains illustrations (primarily proof engravings) by Frederick Walker (1840-1875) and William Makepeace Thackeray (1811-1863), likely comprising the collection of J. G. Marks and annotated by him with title and other contextual information. The volume contains proofs of Frederick Walker's contributions to various periodicals and other items by him, as well as some text and drawings by William Makepeace Thackeray relating to his The Adventures of Philip, as serialized in Cornhill Magazine in 1861-1862, with relevant proofs.
      In total, the album contains 144 images in a range of sizes from 8 x 9 cm to 23 x 17.5 cm, including 125 proof engravings, 5 items of manuscript material by William Makepeace Thackeray, 9 photographs of paintings and engravings by Frederick Walker, 3 designs for the Moray Minstrels, and 2 photographs of Halsway. The proofs consist of contributions to Once A Week, Cornhill Magazine, and Good Words, proofs of the illustrations for The Adventures of Philip and for Thackeray's unfinished novel, Denis Duval, as well as for Oswald Cray by Ellen Wood (Mrs. Henry Wood) and novels by Anne Thackeray Ritchie.
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      AM 2016-110
      Purchased in 2016.
  - Subseries 1B: Bound Manuscripts, 1700-1951; 4 boxes; 138 items; 12 Volumes
    Consists of manuscripts of authors such as Charlotte Brontë, Wilkie Collins, Charles Dickens, George Eliot, Sir Walter Scott, Robert Louis Stevenson, and William Makepeace Thackeray, as well as others.
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Ainsworth, William Harrison, 1805-1882, 1876; 2 items
      - "Chetwynd Calverley", circa 1876; 1 item (Item 27)
        Incomplete autograph manuscript of "Chetwynd Calverley," with numerous deletions and revisions. Including "additional variations," at end.
      - "True Account of Jack Sheppard the Housebreaker...", 1837-1838; 1 item Bound in 2 volumes, the first 4to, red morocco gilt by Riviere & Sons, the second folio, morocco-backed green boards with spine lettered in gilt with material tipped to larger leaves. volume 1, 23.4 x 19.5 cm; volume 2, 30.8 x 22.7 cm (Item 152)
        Manuscript in ink and pencil, comprising a collection of autograph manuscripts, drafts, and notes of the historical novel Jack Sheppard, including the greater part of "Epoch the First" of the novel, "Epoch the Second" and "Epoch the Third"; together with a synopsis of the novel under the earlier title "Scroope Darrell," and historical notes and extracts on the history of Jack Sheppard, with three autograph letters and two engraved portraits of Sheppard and Ainsworth, and fragments from the manuscript of Ainsworth's novel Old St. Paul's (1841) bound with the second volume.
        AM 2016-98
        Purchased at auction, 2016
        Custodial History
        Adrian H. Joline of New York City (his sale, Anderson Galleries, part 9, February 23-24, 1916, Lots 10 and 11); Albert B. Ashforth, Jr. (bookplate in second volume); Arthur A. Houghton (bookplates in each volume; his sale, Christie's London, June 13, 1979, Lot 4
    - Balfour, Graham, Sir, 1859-1929, 1901; 1 item
      - "Life of Stevenson." T. & A. Constable, Printers, Edinburgh, 18 Mar 1901", 1 item (Item 19)
        Stamp on final leaf. Unbound leaves in slipcase.
    - Barrie, James Matthew, 1860-1937, 1900-1937; 1 item
      - "Autograph Letters from J. M. Barrie to Mrs. Thomas Hardy", 1913-1937; 28; 2 Volumes (Volume 1, Volume 2)
        Contains typed transcripts of the original autograph letters.
      - "'Surprise' an Inspired Paragraph", 1900s; 1 item (Item 29)
        Autograph manuscript of Barrie's "'Surprise', an Inspired Paragraph," describing his piece written for a YMCA benefit entitled "The First Real Thing," n.d. Together with a typescript transcription (1 leaf), laid in.
    - Benson, Arthur Christopher, 1862-1925, 1906; 1 item
      - "Charles Kingsley", circa 1906; 1 item (Item 78)
        Typescript of a speech about Charles Kingsley, with autograph corrections and additions. Spine title.
    - Black, William, 1841-1898, 1875-1897; 9 items
      - "The Handsome Humes", 1892; 1 item (Item 30)
        Autograph manuscript of "The Handsome Humes," Brighton.
      - "Ladies Club", 1880s; 1 item (Item 12)
        "Proof to William Black, 4 Catherine Terrace, Lansdowne Road, S.W."
      - "Mad Cap Violet", circa 1897; 1 item (Item 31)
        Autograph manuscript of "Madcap Violet," undated.
      - "The Pupil of Aurelius", undated; 1 item (Item 145)
        Autograph manuscript, bound.
      - "Romeo & Juliet: a Tale of Two Young Fools." "Brighton, April 1886," "To Violet Honner Morton, From her Uncle, Brighton Nov. 13, 1886" (written in pen on front flyleaf). "To my cousin Kenneth Macleod Black on his wedding day. vols. H. M. Richmond, June. 07" (written in pen on front flyleaf), 1 item (Item 32)
      - "Stand Fast, Craig-Royston!" Brighton, 1889; 1 item (Item 33)
      - "Three Feathers", 1875; 1 item (Item 34)
        Incomplete autograph manuscript.
      - "White Heather", 1885; 1 item (Item 35)
        Autograph manuscript.
      - "White Wings: a Yachting Romance", 1880s; 1 item (Item 36)
        Autograph manuscript, undated.
    - Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855, 1822; 2 items
      - "La jeune fille malade", 1822; 1 item (Item 37)
        Signed autograph manuscript, dated Le 18 Avril 1822. Typed English translation, laid in.
      - "La prière du soir dans un camp", circa 1822; 1 item (Item 38)
        Signed autograph manuscript, dated Le 26 Avril. Typed English translation, laid in.
    - Collins, G. W., 1848; 1 item
      - "Paddington Hill", circa 1848; 1 item (Item 40)
        Autograph manuscript of a poem.
    - Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889, 1800-1890; 9 items
      - "Autograph Letters Addressed to Mr. Chatto", 1876-1890; 1 item (Item 41)
        Approximately 130 autograph letters from Collins to Mr. Chatto of Chatto and Windus, discussing the writing of his stories and novels, arrangements for publication, rights of translation, etc.
      - "The Captain's Last Love", 1800s; 1 item (Item 42)
        Original autograph manuscript with annotations and deletions, n.d.
      - "Fallen Leaves", 1870s; 1 item (Item 43)
        Complete autograph manuscript, heavily corrected with many lines scored out and rewritten above, undated. Published in "The World," 1878-79.
      - "The Ghost's Touch", 1870s; 1 item (Item 44)
        Autograph manuscript, heavily corrected with many lines scored out and rewritten above, undated.
      - "Little Novels", 1887; 1 item (Item 45)
        Unbound, corrected page proofs. London: Chatto and Windus, Piccadilly.
      - "Man and Wife", circa 1869-1870; 1 item (Item 46)
      - "Memorandum Relating to the Life and Writings of Wilkie Collins", 1862; 1 item (Item 47)
        Autograph manuscript (4 pp.) containing autobiographical information. Together with 1 autograph letter (4 pp.) from Collins to "Dear Sir," dated 12 Harley Street, Cavendish Square, London.
      - "The Woman in White", circa 1861; 1 item (Item 48)
        Part of the original annotated proof copy. There are four notes to the printer in Collin's hand, initialled by him, on pp. 149, 150, 264, and 312; textual changes on 32 pages, which appear to be in his hand; and some 400 markings throughout by a printer's or publisher's reader, some of which may be by the author (corrections of misprints, changes in punctuation, indications of wrong fonts and of imperfectly printed words, etc.). Written on all but one of the gatherings is the word "Press," which, with two exceptions, has been lined out; also written on most of the gatherings are variously the words "Foundry," "Revise," or "Pull revise." "Machine [?] 10000 Cast" is written on p. 385 and 401. An instruction, "Revisse metal," "Revise metal carefully," "See metal," or "Pull revise," is written on 10 pages. The final leaf (pp. 415-16) is defective, with loss of text.
      - "Fie! Fie! or, The Fair Physician: (Edited, Under the Instructions of Mrs. Crossmichael)", circa 1882; 1 item Leaves mounted on heavier paper and bound in blue levant half-morocco 29.1 x 23.1 cm (Item 151)
        Manuscript in ink with extensive author's revisions throughout, with a double-signed photograph of the author by Sarony pasted down to the verso of the upper cover. (London)
        Wilkie Collins (Sotheby, Wilkinson & Hodge, Catalogue of the Original Manuscripts by Charles Dickens and Wilkie Collins, London, June 18, 1890, Lot 35); American Art Association, Anderson Galleries, New York, 1923, lot 144; Swann, April 21, 1994, lot 131.
    - Craik, Dinah Maria Mulock, 1826-1887, 1860-1879; 4 items
      - "A French Country Family", 1860s; 1 item (Item 49)
      - "A Hero", 1870s; 1 item (Item 50)
        Autograph manuscript of chapters 8-10 of "A hero," undated.
      - "M. de Barante", circa 1867; 1 item (Item 51)
        Autograph manuscript of Craik's English translation of a work by Guizot, undated. Together with "A discourse delivered at the general meeting of the Historical Society of France 7th May 1867 by Mr Guizot, President."
      - "Philip My King", circa 1867; 1 item (Item 53)
        Proof copy of "Philip my King," written by Craik for her godson, Philip Bourke Marston. Later published in "Chamber's Edinburgh Journal," vols. 15, whole no. 374, Mar. 1, 1851, p. 144.
    - Craik, George L. (George Lillie), 1798-1866, 1800-1809; 1 item
      - "Catalogue", 1800s; 1 item (Item 54)
        Autograph manuscript of a library catalog.
    - De La Ramée, Louise, 1839-1908, undated; 1 item
      - "Autographs / Birds / Ouida", undated; 1 item (Item 146)
        A bound volume in full morocco containing: a photograph of Ouida by Julia Margaret Cameron; the original manuscript of Ouida's essay "Birds," 24 pp., with typed transcription; and 4 signed autograph letters--to "Miss Duff," to a journalist of The Times (4 Oct. 1889), to "Mr. Trollope" (possibly Anthony Trollope), to "Mr. Chapman" (1876, probably Frederic Chapman of Chapman & Hall publishers)--with typed transcriptions.
    - Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870, 1851 May 13-1896; 2 items
      - "Ein Weihnachtslied in prosa. Eine Geistergeschichte von Charles Dickens", 1868; 1 item (Item 149)
        Fair copy of an apparently unpublished German translation of Charles Dickens's A Christmas Carol. With handcolored frontispiece drawing, and five decorative initials in the text, 175 pp., bound, presumably, for presentation, in contemporary ribbed cloth, decorated in gilt and blind, all edges gilt. The preface, dated Christmas 1868 and signed "Laura," explains that the translation was done in the hope 'of bringing joy and pleasure' and that 'you may be nothing but satisfied with it.'
      - "Minute Book: Guild of Literature & Art", 1854-1896; 8; 3 Volumes (Volume 1, Volume 2, Volume 3)
        Autograph manuscripts of Guild meeting minutes. Kept by Dickens until his death in 1870.
      - "Original Autograph Letters on Guild of Literature and Art", 1851 May 13-24; 1 item (Item 55)
        Contains two autograph letters signed by Dickens to Joseph Jenkins Esq. (each 2 leaves) relating to the "Guild of Literature and Art" with the original pen-and-ink drawing and 3 proofs which form the subject of the letters.
    - Disraeli, Benjamin, Earl of Beaconsfield, 1804-1881, 1867-1880; 2 items
      - "Endymion.", 1880; 1 item (Item 56)
        Proof copy. "From Spottiswoode & Co. New-Street Square, London, E.C. for [L.] Reader, Esq. Author's proof Sept 20/80"--Stamp, vols. 1, cover.
      - "Newspaper clippings of Disraeli's speeches in Edinburgh", 1867; 1 item (Item 57)
        Newspaper clippings of Disraeli's speeches in Edinburgh, Oct. 29-30, 1867. Pasted down in blank book with manuscript corrections and annotations.
    - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1832-1898. (Lewis Carroll), 1800-1882; 4 boxes; 6 items
      - "Drawings after (Sir John) Tenniel: Alice in Wonderland", 1875 August 3-September 25; 1 item (Item 59)
        Bound series of 8 original postcard drawings (pen-and-ink) signed by "AB", addressed to "Miss Rachel Gray 78 High Street Ilfracombe N. Devon" and also "Miss Rachel Gray 4 Walton Place Leamington."
      - "Introductory Chapter to a Short Treatise on Circle-squaring", 1882; 1 item (Item 60)
        Autograph manuscript to an intoductory chapter concerning circle-squaring. Includes diagrams.
      - "Letter from Dodgson", 1880; 1 item (Item 58)
        Signed autograph letter from Dodgson to Daniel concerning Daniel's request for a poem by Dodgson in honor of his daughter Rachel's first birthday. Together with printed copy of two versions of a poem written by Dodgson. The second poem was printed by Daniel at his private press in Oxford in "Garland of Rachel." The first poem, which reflects Dodgson's dislike for babies, was set up in type for Daniel (not by him) but was never issued.
      - "Problem", 1844; 1 item (Item 61)
        Autograph manuscript concerning geometry.
      - "Rev. C. L. Dodgson's Leather Wallet", 1800s; 1 item (Item 62)
        A leather wallet kept by C. L. Dodgson while traveling in Russia. Dodgson labeled each compartment of this "pocketbook" in manuscript: "1 Stamps, visiting cards, etc.; 2. Envelopes; 3. Note paper; 4. Stamped envelopes; 5. Scrap-book; 6. Letters needing answers; 7. do, not do; 8. Letter-cards; 9 [blank]; 10. Telegraph forms and 6d stamps" and, on the inside, in the same hand, "Rev. C.L. Dodgson, Ch. Ch., Oxford," n.d.
      - "Tour in 1867", 1 item (Item 63)
        Autograph manuscript diary, kept by Dodgson, giving an account of a trip taken by him and Henry P. Liddon to Russia in 1867. Contains one small pen-and-ink drawing on fol. 14v (v. 2).
        This has been published as Tour in 1867... from the Original Manuscript in the Collection of M. L. Parrish, Esq. Pine Valley, New Jersey. Philadelphia: Privately printed, 1928. One of 66 copies privately printed from the original manuscript owned by M. L. Parrish. "A diary by Dodgson of a continental tour in company with Canon Liddon, through Brussels, Cologne, Berlin, and Königsberg, to St. Petersburgh and Moscow, returning by Warsaw, Breslau, Dresden, and Paris, 12 July-14 Sept. 1867." There are two copies in the Parrish book collection.
        Copy 1: Call number: Parrish – Dodgson # 599. Dark red flexible morocco-grained leather. T.e.g. Inscription on free front endpaper: From the Publisher to himself M. L. Parrish Oct 12th 1928.
        Copy 2: Call number: Parrish – Dodgson # 600. Inscription in pencil on free front endpaper: Gift of Mr. Parrish, Dec.–1928. PL. Bookplate of Paul Lemperly.
      - Photograph Albums, undated; 4 boxes (Box 105, Box 106, Box 107, Box 108)
    - Eliot, George, 1819-1880, 1800-1862; 2 items
      - "Quarry for Romola", circa 1861-1862; 1 item (Item 69)
        Manuscript notebook containing notes concerning Savonarola and Florence, which Eliot compiled in 1861 in preparation for the writing of "Romola."
      - "Three Essays", 1800s; 1 item (Item 68)
        Autograph manuscript essays pertaining to the philosophical concepts of life, time, age, etc., undated.
    - Fissenden, Rev., 1700-1709; 1 item
      - "Three Sermons,", 1700s; 1 item (Item 70)
        Ms. sermons, probably written by a Rev. Fissenden of Rolvenden and Newenden Rectories in England (fl. 1687-1737). Sermons topics concern Corinthians 1 10:16, John 3:5, and Ecclesiastes 5:1. Bookplates of Car. I. Taboris. and Godfrey Wills. "Cha. Kingsley, Dulwich" and "Rev. Mr. Fissenden...," written in pen on front flyleaf.
    - Gozzaldi, Mary Isabella, b. 1852, 1932-1933; 1 item
      - "Letters.", 1932-1933; 1 item (Item 72)
        Volume of 4 autograph letters and 1 typed letter to Mr. Madan of the Bodleian Library, Oxford, concerning Gozzaldi's chess table that was part of Falconer Madan's Lewis Carroll Centenary Exhibition in 1932
    - Guizot, M. (François), 1787-1874, 1867; 1 item
      - "M. de Barante.", circa 1867; 1 item (Item 52)
        Corrected page proofs with 2 ALS from Guizot to Craik.
    - Hatch, Beatrice, 1898; 1 item
      - "Lewis Carroll Memorial Cot, &c", 1898; 1 item (Item 64)
        Album of newspaper clippings relation to Lewis Carroll's death, compiled by Hatch.
    - Hatch, Evelyn M., 1932-1933; 1 item
      - "Cuttings: Letters of Lewis Carroll", 1932-1933; 1 item (Item 65)
        Album of newspaper clippings, "Letters of Lewis Carroll Reviews."
    - Holiday, Henry, 1839-1927, 1876-1923; 1 item
      - "Original Sketches for the Hunting of the Snark, Henry Holiday", circa 1876-1923; 1 item (Item 9)
        Contains original "Snark" drawings, engravers' proofs, and autograph letters, tipped in. Correspondence includes letter from Henry Holiday regarding the proofs and certain comments from Lewis Carroll (4 pp.) dated March 13th, 1922; autograph letter from George Sutcliffe, who was in personal communication with Mr. Holliday (2 pp.) dated March 24th, 1922; two letters from Henry Holiday to Henry Smith, one dated March 12th, 1923, the other "18-5-23" regarding sale of the book "Hunting of the Snark"; autograph letter from Henry Holiday to Henry Smith with thanks for payment of "Hunting of the Snark" (4 pp.) dated December 8, 1923.
    - Hudson, Derek, 1900-1909; 1 item
      - "Lewis Carroll", 1900s; 66; 9 Volumes (Volume 1, Volume 2, Volume 3, Volume 4, Volume 5, Volume 6, Volume 7, Volume 8, Volume 9)
        Autograph manuscript of a biography of Lewis Carroll.
      - "Lewis Carroll", 1900s; 1 item (Item 67)
        Autograph manuscript of a first draft of a British Council pamphlet.
    - Hughes Family, 1800-1809; 1 item
      - "Photograph Album", 1800s; 71; 1 item